<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>List of institutions</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <p/>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>Generated from data</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <list>
                <item xml:id="bm_Abbadie1859Cat">Abbadie, A. d’ 1859. <i>Catalogue raisonné de manuscrits éthiopiens appartenant à Antoine d’Abbadie</i> (Paris: Imprimerie impériale, 1859).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Unesco1970Manuscripts">Anon. 1970. <i>Catalogue of Manuscripts Microfilmed: Ethiopian Monastries</i> (Addis Ababa: Ministry of Education and Fine Arts-Department of Fine Arts and Culture, 1970).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_appleyard1993EthiopianManuscripts">Appleyard, D. 1993. <i>Ethiopian Manuscripts</i> (London: Jed Press, 1993).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Assemani1719Bibliotheca">Assemani, G. S. 1719. <i>Bibliotheca Orientalis Clementino-Vaticana: In qua manuscriptos codices Syriacos, Arabicos, Persicos, Turcicos, Hebraicos, Samaritanos, Armenicos, Aethiopicos, Graecos, Aegyptiacos, Ibericos, &amp; Malabaricos, jussu et munificentia Clementis XI. Pontificis Maximi ex Oriente conquisitos, comparatos, avectos, &amp; Bibliothecae Vaticanae addictos</i> (Romae: Typis Sacræ Congregationis de Propaganda Fide, 1719).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Bausi1989MssBNCF">Bausi, A. 1991. ‘I manoscritti etiopici di J.M. Wansleben nella biblioteca nazionale centrale di Firenze’, <i>Rassegna di Studi Etiopici</i>, 33 (1989) (1991), 5–33.</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_RIE1">Bernand, É., A. J. Drewes, and R. Schneider 1991. <i>Recueil des inscriptions de l’Éthiopie des périodes pré-axoumite et axoumite, Introduction de Fr. Anfray, <span style="font-style:normal;">I: </span>Les documents</i> (Paris: Diffusion de Boccard, 1991).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Bezold1905KebraN">Bezold, C. 1905. <i>Kebra Nagast: Die Herrlichkeit der Könige, Nach den Handschriften in Berlin, London, Oxford und Paris zum ersten Mal im äthiopischen Urtext herausgegeben und mit deutscher Übersetzung versehen</i>, ed., tr. C. Bezold, 1st, Abhandlungen der K. Bayer. Akademie der Wiss. I. Kl., 23 (München: Verlag der K. Akademie der Wissenschaften in Kommission des G. Franz’schen Verlags (J. Roth), 1905).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Bolotov1887Manuscripts">Bolotov, V. 1887. ‘Opisanie dvuch" rukopisej, požertvovannych" v" biblioteku Spb. Duch. Akademii preosvjaščennym" Anatoliem", episkopom" baltskim" (nyně ostrogožskim")’, <i>Christianskoe čtenije</i>, 7–8 (1887), 137–160.</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Brockelmann1908KatalogHamburg">Brockelmann, C. 1908. <i>Katalog der orientalischen Handschriften der Stadtbibliothek zu Hamburg: mit Ausschluss der hebräischen, Teil I, die arabischen, persischen, türkischen, malaiischen, koptischen, syrischen, äthiopischen Handschriften</i> (Hamburg: Otto Meissner, 1908).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Cerulli1946IO">Cerulli, E. 1946. ‘I manoscritti etiopici della biblioteca dell’India Office in Londra’, <i>Oriente Moderno</i>, 26/7–12 (1946), 109–116.</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Chaine1912Catalogue">Chaîne, M. 1912. <i>Catalogue des manuscrits éthiopiens de la Collection Antoine d’Abbadie</i> (Paris: Imprimerie nationale–Ernest Leroux, éditeur, 1912).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Chaine1913Mondon">Chaîne, M. 1913. <i>Catalogue des manuscrits éthiopiens de la collection Mondon-Vidailhet</i> (Paris: Ernest Leroux, 1913).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_ContiRossini1914Notice">Conti Rossini, C. 1914. <i>Notice sur les manuscrits éthiopiens de la Collection d’Abbadie</i>, Extrait du Journal Asiatique (Paris: Imprimerie nationale, 1914).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Derat2016DL">Derat, M.-L. 2016. ‘Autour de l’homélie en l’honneur du saint-roi Lâlibalâ: écritures hagiographiques, copies et milieux de production’, eds H. Kaufhold and M. Kropp, Oriens Christianus: Hefte für die Kunde des christlichen Orients, 99 (2016), 101–132.</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Dillmann1847BM">Dillmann, C. F. A. 1847. <i>Catalogus codicum manuscriptorum orientalium qui in Museo Britannico asservantur, Pars tertia: Codices Aethiopicos amplectens</i> (London: British Museum, 1847).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Dillmann1848Catalogus">Dillmann, C. F. A. 1848. <i>Catalogus codicum manuscriptorum Bibliothecae Bodleianae Oxoniensis, Pars VII: Codices Aethiopici</i> (Oxonii: E Typographeo Academico, 1848).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_EthioSpare">
                    <i>DomLib/Ethio-SPARE Manuscript Cataloguing Database</i> (Database) (2009) &lt;http://mycms-vs03.rrz.uni-hamburg.de/domlib/&gt;.</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Dorn1852Catalogue">Dorn, B. 1852. <i>Catalogue des manuscrits et xylographes orientaux de la Bibliothèque Impériale Publique de St. Pétersbourg</i> (St Petersburg: Imprimerie de l’Académie Impèriale des Sciences, 1852).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_EMML">
                    <i>EMML = Ethiopian Manuscript Microfilm Library, Addis Ababa - Collegeville, MN</i> &lt;http://www.hmml.org/emml.html&gt;.</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Falivene1982Catalogue">Falivene, M. R. and A. F. Jesson 1982. <i>Historical Catalogue of the Manuscripts in Bible House Library</i> (London: The British and Foreign Bible Society, 1982).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Fiaccadori2007Adulitanum">Fiaccadori, G. 2007. ‘Monumentum Adulitanum’, in <i>Encyclopaedia Aethiopica</i>, III (Wiesbaden: Harrassowitz Verlag, 2007), 1010a-1012b.</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_2007fiaccadori">Fiaccadori, G. 2007. ‘Nuova Iscrizione Greca di Aksum’, <i>La Parole del Passato. Rivista di Studi Antichi</i>, 62 (2007), 70–76.</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_EMML4">Getatchew Haile 1979. <i>A Catalogue of Ethiopian Manuscripts Microfilmed for the Ethiopian Manuscript Microfilm Library, Addis Ababa, and for the Hill Monastic Manuscript Library, Collegeville, IV: Project Numbers 1101–1500</i> (Collegeville, MN: Hill Monastic Manuscript Library, St. John’s Abbey and University, 1979).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_EMML8">Getatchew Haile 1985. <i>A Catalogue of Ethiopian Manuscripts Microfilmed for the Ethiopian Manuscript Microfilm Library, Addis Ababa, and for the Hill Monastic Manuscript Library, Collegeville, VIII: Project Numbers 3001–3500</i> (Collegeville, MN: Hill Monastic Manuscript Library, St. John’s Abbey and University, 1985).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_EMML9">Getatchew Haile 1987. <i>A Catalogue of Ethiopian Manuscripts Microfilmed for the Ethiopian Manuscript Microfilm Library, Addis Ababa, and for the Hill Monastic Manuscript Library, Collegeville, IX: Project Numbers 3501–4000</i> (Collegeville, MN: Hill Monastic Manuscript Library, St. John’s Abbey and University, 1987).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_EMML10">Getatchew Haile 1993. <i>A Catalogue of Ethiopian Manuscripts Microfilmed for the Ethiopian Manuscript Microfilm Library, Addis Ababa, and for the Hill Monastic Manuscript Library, Collegeville, X: Project Numbers 4001–5000</i> (Collegeville, MN: Hill Monastic Manuscript Library, St. John’s University, 1993).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_EMML5">Getatchew Haile and W. F. Macomber 1981. <i>A Catalogue of Ethiopian Manuscripts Microfilmed for the Ethiopian Manuscript Microfilm Library, Addis Ababa, and for the Hill Monastic Manuscript Library, Collegeville, V: Project Numbers 1501–2000</i> (Collegeville, MN: Hill Monastic Manuscript Library, St. John’s Abbey and University, 1981).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_EMML6">Getatchew Haile and W. F. Macomber 1982. <i>A Catalogue of Ethiopian Manuscripts Microfilmed for the Ethiopian Manuscript Microfilm Library, Addis Ababa, and for the Hill Monastic Manuscript Library, Collegeville, VI: Project Numbers 2001–2500</i> (Collegeville, MN: Hill Monastic Manuscript Library, St. John’s Abbey and University, 1982).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_EMML7">Getatchew Haile and W. F. Macomber 1983. <i>A Catalogue of Ethiopian Manuscripts Microfilmed for the Ethiopian Manuscript Microfilm Library, Addis Ababa, and for the Hill Monastic Manuscript Library, Collegeville, VII: Project Numbers 2501–3000</i> (Collegeville, MN: Hill Monastic Manuscript Library, St. John’s Abbey and University, 1983).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Goldschmidt1897catalogue">Goldschmidt, L. 1897. <i>Die Abessinischen Handschriften der Stadtbibliothek zu Frankfurt am Main (Rüppell’sche Sammlung) nebst Anhängen und Auszügen</i> (Berlin: Calvary, 1897).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_GrebTiss1935Codices">Grébaut, S. and E. Tisserant 1935. <i>Bybliothecae apostolicae Vaticanae codices manu scripti recensiti iussu Pii XI Pontificis maximi. Codices Aethiopici Vaticani et Borgiani, Barberinianus orientalis 2, Rossianus 865<span style="font-style:normal;">, I:</span> Enarratio codicum</i> (Città del Vaticano: In Bybliotheca Vaticana, 1935).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Hammerschmidt1973Tanasee">Hammerschmidt, E. 1973. <i>Äthiopische Handschriften vom Ṭānāsee 1: Reisebericht und Beschreibung der Handschriften in dem Kloster des Heiligen Gabriel auf der Insel Kebrān</i>, Verzeichnis der orientalischen Handschriften in Deutschland, 20/1 (Wiesbaden: Franz Steiner Verlag GmbH, 1973).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Huntingford1987Historicalgeo">Huntingford, G. W. B. 1989. <i>The Historical Geography of Ethiopia from the First Century AD to 1704</i>, ed. R. Pankhurst, Fontes historiae Africanae, Series varia, 4 (Oxford: Oxford University Press, 1989).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_DAE2">Krencker, D. and T. von Lüpke 1913. <i>Deutsche Aksum-Expedition, II: Ältere Denkmäler Nordabessiniens. Mit einem Anhang von Robert Zahn</i> (Berlin: Verlag von Georg Reimer, 1913).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Littmann1902Jerusalem">Littmann, E. 1902. ‘Aus den abessinischen Klöstern in Jerusalem’, <i>Zeitschrift für Assyriologie und verwandte Gebiete</i>, 16 (1902), 102–124, 363–388.</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Ludolf1691Commentarius">Ludolf, H. 1691. <i>Ad suam Historiam Aethiopicam antehac editam Commentarius: in quo multa breviter dicta fusius narrantur, contraria refelluntur, Atque hac occasione praeter res Aethiopicas multa Autorum, quaedam etiam S. Scripturae loca declarantur...</i> (Francofurti ad Moenum: Sumptibus Johannis David Zunneri, 1691).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_EuringerLoefgren1932Anaphoren">Löfgren, O. and S. Euringer 1932. ‘Die beiden äthiopischen Anaphoren “des heiligen Cyrillus, Patriarchen von Alexandrien”’, <i>Zeitschrift für Semitistik und verwandte Gebiete</i>, 8 (1932), 210–234.</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_EMML1">Macomber, W. F. 1975. <i>A Catalogue of Ethiopian Manuscripts Microfilmed for the Ethiopian Manuscript Microfilm Library, Addis Ababa, and for the Monastic Manuscript Microfilm Library, Collegeville, I: Project Numbers 1–300</i> (Collegeville, MN: Monastic Manuscript Microfilm Library, St. John’s Abbey and University, 1975).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_EMML2">Macomber, W. F. 1976. <i>A Catalogue of Ethiopian Manuscripts Microfilmed for the Ethiopian Manuscript Microfilm Library, Addis Ababa, and for the Hill Monastic Manuscript Library, Collegeville, II: Project Numbers 301–700</i> (Collegeville, MN: Hill Monastic Manuscript Library, St. John’s Abbey and University, 1976).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_EMML3">Macomber, W. F. 1978. <i>A Catalogue of Ethiopian Manuscripts Microfilmed for the Ethiopian Manuscript Microfilm Library, Addis Ababa, and for the Hill Monastic Manuscript Library, Collegeville, III: Project Numbers 701–1100</i> (Collegeville, MN: Hill Monastic Manuscript Library, St. John’s Abbey and University, 1978).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Marrassini1986Laurenziana">Marrassini, P. 1984. ‘I Manoscritti Etiopici della Biblioteca Medicea Laurenziana di Firenze’, <i>Rassegna di Studi Etiopici</i>, 30 (1984), 81–116.</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Marrassini1987manoscrittietiopici">Marrassini, P. 1987. ‘I manoscritti etiopici della Biblioteca Medicea Laurenziana di Firenze’, <i>Rassegna di Studi Etiopici</i>, 31 (1987), 69–110.</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_marrassini2014Iscrizioni">Marrassini, P. 2014. <i>Storia e leggenda dell’Etiopia tardoantica: Le iscrizioni reali aksumite</i>, ed. P. Marrassini, Testi del Vicino Oriente antico, 9, Letteratura etiopica, 1 (Brescia: Paideia Editrice, 2014).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Marrassini1995YK">Marrassini, P., ed., 1995. <i>Il Gadla Yemreḥanna Krestos: introduzione, testo critico, traduzione</i>, tr. P. Marrassini, Supplemento agli Annali, 55/4 (1995), 85 (Napoli: Istituto Universitario Orientale, 1995).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Mueller1862Wien">Müller, F. 1862. ‘Die äthiopischen Handschriften der K. K. Hofbibliothek zu Wien’, <i>Zeitschrift der Deutschen Morgenländischen Gesellschaft</i>, 16 (1862), 553–557.</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Nicoll1821Bodleianae">Nicoll, A. 1821. <i>Bibliothecae Bodleianae codicum manuscriptorum orientalium catalogi
                    partis secundae volumen primum arabicos complectens</i> (Oxonii: E typographeo clarendoniano, 1821).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Piovanelli2014Kebra">Piovanelli, P. 2014. ‘“Orthodox” Faith and Political Legitimization of a “Solomonic” Dynasty of Rulers in the Ethiopic Kebra Nagast. Essays Presented in Honour of Professor Robert W. Thomson on the Occasion of His Eightieth Birthday’, in K. B. Bardakjian and S. La Porta, eds, <i>The Armenian Apocalyptic Tradition. A Comparative Perspective</i> (Leiden–Boston: Brill, 2014), 688–705.</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Platonov1996Katalog">Platonov, V. 1996. <i>Efiopskie rukopisi v sobranijakh Sankt-Peterburga: Katalog</i> (St Petersburg: The Russian National Library Press, 1996).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Platonov2017RukKniga">Platonov, V. 2017. <i>Rukopisnaja kniga v traditsionnoj kulture vostoka</i>, ed. E. Gusarova (Sankt-Peterburg: Rossijskaja natsional’naja biblioteka, 2017).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Platt1823Catalogue">Platt, T. P. 1823. <i>A catalogue of the Ethiopic Biblical manuscripts in the Royal Library of Paris, and in the library of the British and Foreign Bible Society : also some account of those in the Vatican Library at Rome</i> (London: Printed by R. Watts, 1823).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Proverbio2000">Proverbio, D. V. 2000. ‘Inventario sommario dei manoscritti arabi, ebraici, etiopici – con notizia dei turchi – conservati presso la Biblioteca della Badia di Grottaferrata’, <i>Atti della Accademia Nazionale dei Lincei. Classe di scienze morali, storiche e filologiche. Memorie</i>, ser. 9a, 12/4 (2000), 468–570.</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Raineri2004CerulliEtiopici">Raineri, O. 2004. <i>Enrico Cerulli. Inventario dei manoscritti Cerulli etiopici</i>, Studi e Testi, 420, Cataloghi sommari e inventari dei fondi manoscritti, 8 (Città del Vaticano: Biblioteca Apostolica Vaticana, 2004).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Rhodokanakis1906Handschriften">Rhodokanakis, N. 1906. <i>Die äthiopischen Handschriften der K. K. Hofbibliothek zu Wien</i>, Sitzungsberichte der kais. Akademie der Wissenschaften in Wien. Philosophisch-Historische Klasse, 151 (Wien: In Kommission bei Alfred Hölder, 1906).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Six1989Bayerische">Six, V. 1989. <i>Äthiopische Handschriften 2: Die Handschriften der Bayerischen Staatsbibliothek</i>, ed. E. Hammerschmidt, Verzeichnis der orientalischen Handschriften in Deutschland, 20/5 (Stuttgart: Franz Steiner Verlag Wiesbaden GmbH, 1989).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Six1994VOHD6">Six, V. 1994. <i>Äthiopische Handschriften 3: Handschriften deutscher Bibliotheken, Museen und aus Privatbesitz</i>, ed. E. Hammerschmidt, Verzeichnis der orientalischen Handschriften in Deutschland, 20/6 (Stuttgart: Franz Steiner Verlag, 1994).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Strelcyn1954Griaule">Strelcyn, S. 1954. <i>Catalogue des manuscrits éthiopiens (Collection Griaule). Tome IV: Éthiopien 373 (Griaule 69) - Éthiopien 301-304, 675-687</i> (Paris: Imprimerie nationale, 1954).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Strelcyn1976Catalogue">Strelcyn, S. 1976. <i>Catalogue des manuscrits éthiopiens de l’Accademia Nazionale dei Lincei: Fonds Conti Rossini et Fonds Caetani 209, 375, 376, 377, 378</i>, Indici e Sussidi Bibliografici della Biblioteca, 9 (Roma: Accademia Nazionale dei Lincei, 1976).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_budge1929">The Bandlet of Righteousness, an Ethiopian Book of the Dead. Budge, S. E. A. W. 1929. <i>The Bandlet of Righteousness, an Ethiopian Book of the Dead: The Ethiopic Text of the [Lefāfa Ṣedeq] : in Facsimile from Two Manuscripts in the British Museum</i> (New York, NY: AMS Press, 1929).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Turaev1895Saatat">Turaev, B. 1895. <i>Časoslov’ ėfi̇opskoj cerkvi: izd. i perev. na osnovanii něskol’kich’ rukopisej</i>, Zapiski Imperatorskoj Akademii Nauk po Istoriko-Filologičeskomu Otděleniju, 7 (St. Pétersbourg: Acad. Imp. des Sciences, 1895).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Turaev1906rukopisi">Turaev, B. 1906. <i>Ėfiopskija rukopisi v S.-Peterburgě</i>, Pamjatniki ėfiopskoj pis’mennosti, 3 (St Petersburg: Tipografija imperatorskoj Akademii Nauk, 1906).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Ullendorff1951Catalogue">Ullendorff, E. 1951. <i>Catalogue of Ethiopian manuscripts in the Bodleian Library</i> (Oxford: Clarendon Press, 1951).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Uri1787Catalogus">Uri, J. 1787. <i>Bibliothecae Bodleianae codicum manuscriptorum orientalium, videlicet hebraicorum, chaldaicorum, syriacorum, aethiopicorum, arabicorum, persicorum, turcicorum, copticorumque, catalogus</i>, I (Oxonii: E typographeo clarendoniano, 1787).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Valieva2016GL">Valieva, N. <i>The Portrait of a Queen: A story about a manuscript and its commissione</i> <i>Centre for the Study of Manuscript Cultures</i> (2016) &lt;https://www.manuscript-cultures.uni-hamburg.de/mom/2016_07_mom_e.html&gt;.</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_WolskaConusCosma">Wolska-Conus, W., ed., 1968. <i>Cosmas Indicopleustès. Topographie Chrétienne</i>, I (Paris: Cerf, 1968).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Wright1877BM">Wright, W. 1877. <i>Catalogue of the Ethiopic Manuscripts in the British Museum Acquired since the Year 1847</i> (Piccadilly, Covent Garden–Berlin: Longmans &amp; CO., Asher &amp; CO., 1877).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Zotenberg1874Catalogue">Zotenberg, H. 1874. <i>Catalogues des manuscrits syriaques et sabéens (mandaïtes) de la Bibliothèque nationale</i>, Manuscrits orientaux (Paris: Imprimerie nationale, 1874).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Zotenberg1877Catalogue">Zotenberg, H. 1877. <i>Catalogue des manuscrits éthiopiens (gheez et amharique) de la Bibliothèque nationale</i>, Manuscrits Orientaux (Paris: Imprimerie nationale, 1877).</item>
                <item xml:id="bm_Ewald1844Tuebingen">von Ewald, H. 1844. ‘Ueber die Aethiopischen Handschriften in Tübingen’, <i>Zeitschrift für die Kunde des Morgenlandes</i>, 5 (1844), 164–201.</item>
            </list>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>